Maximiliano Manuel Schier

Nationality: Argentinian

Languages: English/Spanish

Contact: maximiliano.schier@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/maximilianoschier

Profile

Certified AWS Solutions Architect Associate & System Engineer with 10+ years' experience in IT environments. Involved in developing, integrating, and monitoring complex software developments, as well as speaking both Spanish and English. Passionate about interacting and learning new technologies. I am keen to work in challenging and diverse environment where I can continue to grow both professionally & personally, with a proactive attitude and a product mindset.

Areas of Knowledge

- Developing with Python + AWS services.
- Good knowledge of Python frameworks (Reflex, Django).
- Working with AWS since 2019 and several of their most important services (EC2, RDS, S3).
- Infrastructure as code with terraform.
- Troubleshooting and debuggin different applications errors.
- Experience working in an Agile / Scrum environments.

Professional Experience

Queue-it - Solutions Architect (January 2023 – Present)

Develop and help integrating with Queue-it platform.

- Working with Javascript, Python, PHP, .NET.
- Use Reflex Python to develop FrontEnd components.
- Troubleshoot and debug web applications in different platforms.
- Deploy code to Queuefront. Using CDK and .NET components.

Philip Morris International - AWS Solutions Architect / Integration Engineer (February 2021 – January 2023)

Develop, integrate and support AWS and SAP environments.

- Working with boto3.
- Use Python scripts to transfer and integrate files with different apps.
- Automate upload transcripts from Amazon Connect with Lambda.
- Deploy infrastructure using terraform.

Pluspetrol S.A. – Sr Technology and DBA Analyst (February 2020 – February 2021)

- Scripting with Python.
- Analyzed the SQL scripts and designed the solution to developed a custom ETL pipeline by using Python.
- Implemented security policies in AWS (SSH Keys, volumen encryption

Cognizant – Sr Technology and DBA Consultant (June 2019 – February 2020)

Ensured AWS Cloud Infrastructure systems availability. DevOps best practices.

Bunge S.A. - Technology Analyst and Oracle DBA (September 2014 – June 2019)

Successfully supported 35 Productive instances (both SAP + Oracle). Improved 35% response time and had 99.1% Production systems available. DevOps culture.

IBM – SAP Technology Consultant (November 2011 – September 2014)

Played an active role in the support team through collaborating with wide issues and new software implementations.

Invenzis – SAP Basis and Security Consultant (November 2010 – November 2011)

Successfully implemented new SAP Netweaver technology and deployed new functionalities across the company.

Accenture – SAP Basis Administrator (December 2009 – November 2010)

Played an active role in the support team through collaborating with different clients and presented production reports.

Education

Systems Engineer – Universidad Abierta Interamericana (UAI) (2011-2019)

Key Skills & Competencies

- Strong programming foundation.
- Passionate about cloud-based services.
- Effective communication skills, both written and verbal.
- Experience with distributed systems, algorithms, and relational databases.
- Proficiency to quickly adapt to new roles and be flexible within all working conditions.
- Ability to Identify areas where to automate as much as possible.
- Vast experienced with incremental software development, with focus on fast product delivery.
- Confidence in decision-making processes.
- Ability to prioritize key work schedules to meet all deadlines.
- Flexible to work within adverse and challenging conditions.